

# Résumé Of Md. Anisur Rahmen

**①** 01673-271595, 01708-158035

⊠ muctaraj@gmail.com

https://dev-anis-rahmen.pantheonsite.io/

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

I'd love to be a true management information expert with successful end-to-end management experience under my belt as I look to grow into a more senior market analyst role. I love to work with dealers, retailers and ultimate consumers for information system development in order to meet our business objectives or overcome problems. Reporting, graphs, instant information, data reconciliation and manipulation are my day to day activities.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

April 2017 - present

ASST. MANAGER-MIS (SALES DATA ANALYST & REPORTING) – Meghna Pulp & Paper Mills Ltd Gulshan-01. Dhaka.

#### **Key Responsibility**

- + Mining **data** from primary and secondary sources then reorganizing said **data** in a format.
- + Utilized SAP software to track and analyze data.
- + Cross check the information which is given by field force (Such as Stock, Sales, Damage, Memo etc)
- + Follow-up field force daily activities and daily tour plan by software locators.
- + Market survey to gather specific information to support MPPMLs upcoming product/SKU etc, and constructive reporting on categorical pricing, availability and market potentiality as per management required.
- + Varify the promotional Programe activities by physically and liaison with concerned area.
- + Retail outlets to check product-availability, conduct gap-analysis and share with concerned Sales Team.
- + Conduct structured cross-verification audits of claims on products, offerings, complains etc. in the course of day-to-day MPPML sales operation.
- + Prepare special MIS findings report for monthly National Meeting and inform the actual market scenario of respective area.
- + Evaluate the employee performance (Ach%, and Growth)
- + To monitor the delivery from the distribution centers, to ensure the products are delivered in an accurate and timely manner.
- + To handle questions or complaints and offer solutions to customer and dealers regarding finished product delivery.
- + To develop and implement a logistics process and distribute finished products.
- + Monitor progress of major deliveries to ensure receipt.

#### April 2012 – March 2017

#### DIVISIONAL MIS OFFICER- Abul Khair Tobacco Co. Ltd

Pahartoli, Chittagong.

#### **Key Responsibility**

- + Physical verification of Floor Stock.
- + Primary & Secondary Sales Verification of filed force.
- + To cross check Attendance register of Field force.
- + Memo checking for price cut, under rate, over rate & trade offers.
- + To check stock register of Field force & Dealer.
- + Communicate frequently with sales personnel for ROI, ADS, RADS checking.
- + Verification of route chart, market relation, target achievement record etc.
- + Check out delivery activities & sales out of the day.
- + Find out any types of corruption and prevention of fraud
- + Verify distributors claims such as display bill, commission and incentive bill e.t.c.
- + Visit Outlets to find out Irregular service, uncovered service and out of stock.
- + Look for whether promotional programs are implemented properly or not.
- + Perform other investigative jobs and market research assigned by management.

July 2010 - March 2012

#### TERRITORY SALES OFFICER- Abul Khair Tobacco Co. Ltd

Pahartoli, Chittagong.

## **Key Responsibility**

- + Arrange morning meeting and target distribution to AMO by Zone Wise.
- + Ensure manpower participation.
- + Maintain Attendance book, DSS and morning meeting register.
- + Check AMO and SR activities in their schedule Route.
- + Build relation with retailer.
- + In evening sales collect from TSO.
- + Check SR's DSS after complete their development.
- + Ensure training for SR for their development.
- + Ensure display and product visibility.
- + Target Distribution to TSO, AMO and SR.
- Last month sales and market share analysis.
- + Ensure DD and TT by distributor in right time.
- Ensure buffer stock in territory house.
- + Identify and solve the problem of market.
- + Super visional work for SR.
- + Check distributor bill & profit and loss statement.
- + Maintain demand sheet, tour plan gift statement, etc.

Jan 2006 - June 2010

### **BRANCH MANAGER**-omeca

Malopara, Rajshahi.

#### **Key Responsibility**

- + General checking on Daily report, monthly report, stock report and send to the head office.
- + Maintains and directs the orderliness and worry-free environment of the organization.
- + Assist with preparation of monthly budget.
- + Customer handling, problem solving & decision-making.
- + Plan of Marketing & Local Management
- + Assist with preparation and advertising of contract documents
  - Directing all operational aspects including distribution, customer service, human resources, administration and sales in accordance with the bank's objectives

# EDUCATION

2011	MASTERS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION CGPA-3.454 Major-Marketing, University of Rajshahi
2006	MASTERS OF ARTS SECOND CLASS Major-Islamic History & Culture, National University
2005	BECHALOR OF ARTS SECOND CLASS Major-Islamic History & Culture, National University
2001	HIGHER SCHOOL CERTIFICATE FIRST CLASS Humanities, Rajshahi Court College
1999	SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE SECOND CLASS Humanities, Shohid Mamun Mahmud High School, Rajshahi

# TRAINING & CERTIFICATION SUMMARY

u	2021	UDEMY CERTIFICATE COURSE ON WEB DEVELOPMENT FUNDAMENTALS
u	2021	UDEMY CERTIFICATE COURSE ON AFFILIATE MARKETING
u	2021	UDEMY CERTIFICATE COURSE ON ECOMMERCE
u	2020	UDEMY CERTIFICATE COURSE ON BUSINESS ANALYSIS & REQUIREMENTS LIFE CYCLE MGT.
u	2020	UDEMY CERTIFICATE COURSE ON NEXT-LEVEL LINKEDIN MARKETING
u	2020	UDEMY CERTIFICATE COURSE ON MICROSOFT EXCEL PIVOT TABLES & PIVOT CHARTS
Magina Group of Installed	2017	MEGHNA GROUP OF INDUSTRIES TRAINING ON SAP (SD & MM MODULE)
ST CONTROL OF THE PROPERTY OF	2005	QUANTUM FOUNDATION TRAINING ON MEDITATION

SPECIALIZATION			
	+ Pro-active & able to work under pressure.		
	+ Team player and leadership skills.		
	+ Committed to providing total quality.		
	+ analytical and problem solving skills		
PERSONAL INFO			
Father's Name	Late Abdul Hamid		
Mother's Name	Mrs. Ashma Khatun		
Present Address	Road#01, Moddho Badda, Gulshan-01, Dhaka.		
Permanent Address	179, Nawabgong Ghoshpara, Rajpara, Rajshahi, GPO-6000		
Date of Birth	15-12-1984		
Height	5'10''		
Religion	Islam		
Nationality	Bangladeshi		
PROJECT DONE			
	Logo promotion of <u>www.freelancer.com</u>		
	The world-wide logo promotion competition of free-lancer.com website I am taken interest within the competition and sent a video-footage By the grace of Almighty Alla		
	got the first prize in 2011.		
LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY			
	Have excellent command in both English and Bengali.		
COMPUTER SKILL			
Operating System	SAP-ERP, Windows (up to date)		
Application	Advance MS Office, HTML, CSS, GitHub, Wordpress (Web Design), & Photoshop.		
REFERENCE (S)			
	Reference (1)	Reference (2)	
	Shah Jalal Chowdhury	K.M. Iftekhar Mahmud	
	Asst. General Manager, Accounts	Manager, Shah Cement	
	Meghna Group of Industries	Abul Khair Group	
		⊕ 01985559022	
	A CONTRACTOR OF THE PARTY OF TH		
	<del></del>		

Signature of the Applicant